<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C on Inomoz</title><link>https://inomoz.com/tags/c/</link><description>Recent content in C on Inomoz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 18:28:56 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://inomoz.com/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Escape Sequences</title><link>https://inomoz.com/posts/20220119215704-escape_sequences/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 18:28:56 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://inomoz.com/posts/20220119215704-escape_sequences/</guid><description>&lt;p>Combination of characters, which meaning something other than the literal characters contained therein.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Usually 2 characters, one is preceding and second is actual character (which explain that escape sequence).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Escape_sequences_in_C#ref_Note1">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Escape_sequences_in_C#ref_Note1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>\a 07 Alert (Beep, Bell) (added in C89)[1]
\b 08 Backspace
\e 1B Escape character (non standart)
\f 0C Formfeed Page Break
\n 0A Newline (Line Feed); see notes below
\r 0D Carriage Return
\t 09 Horizontal Tab
\v 0B Vertical Tab
\\ 5C Backslash
\' 27 Apostrophe or single quotation mark
\&amp;quot; 22 Double quotation mark
\? 3F Question mark (used to avoid trigraphs)
\nnnnote 2 any The byte whose numerical value is given by nnn interpreted as an octal number
\xhh… any The byte whose numerical value is given by hh… interpreted as a hexadecimal number
\uhhhhnote 3 none Unicode code point below 10000 hexadecimal (added in C99)[1]: 26
\Uhhhhhhhhnote 4 none Unicode code point where h is a hexadecimal digit&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/hectoregm/1368066">https://gist.github.com/hectoregm/1368066&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Escape Sequence Name Meaning
\a Alert Produces an audible or visible alert.
\b Backspace Moves the cursor back one position (non-destructive).
\f Form Feed Moves the cursor to the first position of the next page.
\n New Line Moves the cursor to the first position of the next line.
\r Carriage Return Moves the cursor to the first position of the current line.
\t Horizontal Tab Moves the cursor to the next horizontal tabular position.
\v Vertical Tab Moves the cursor to the next vertical tabular position.
\' Produces a single quote.
\&amp;quot; Produces a double quote.
\? Produces a question mark.
\\ Produces a single backslash.
\0 Produces a null character.
\ddd Defines one character by the octal digits (base-8 number). Multiple characters may be defined in the same escape sequence, but the value is implementation-specific (see examples).
\xdd Defines one character by the hexadecimal digit (base-16 number).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>